《星际之门亚特兰蒂斯》  前情回顾
Previously on stargate atlantis...
你给我每周注射的药物
The weekly injection you gave me, that must have been
一定是要能阻止我细胞恶化的
some kind of drug to keep my cells from deteriorating.
听着  我们会一直努力下去
Listen, we're going to keep working
直到治愈你为止
till we find a cure for this thing.
中头奖了
jackpot.
这是个陷阱  我们要马上离开这
It's a booby trap. We got to get out of here now!
把工程兵集合起来
Have the combat engineers gear up,
叫凯勒医生准备好
and have dr. Keller ready her away team.
你听
Listen...
这是迈克尔的数据库
it's michael's database.
里面有大量甚至所有的资料
There's a large chunk of it, maybe the whole thing.
他正在仓忙出逃  我们快要抓住他了
We'd have him on the run. He'd be finished.
你被免除指挥官一职
Effective immediately,
即刻起生效
you are being removed from command.
谁来代替我
Who-who's replacing me?
是我
I am.
下午好  凯勒医生
Good afternoon, dr.Keller.
我的新病人怎么样了
How's my newest patient?
今天  只有我一直抱着他散步
Today, he's decided that he will only sleep
他才肯乖乖睡觉
as long as I hold him and keep moving.
我已经在转了大半个城市  现在要转回去
I've already walked half the city and back again.
我父母以前把我放进车里
My parents used to put me in the car.
然后爸爸凌晨3点开车带着我
My dad would have to drive around and around and around
在街区转来转去
the block 3:00 in the morning.
真温馨啊  至少能坐着
That would be lovely. At least I'd be sitting down.
我要谢谢你
I wanted to thank you.
为什么
For what?
我今天见过迦楠了
I saw kanaan today.
他怎么样了
How's he doing?
比以前好多了
Much better.
他各方面都回到原来的样子了
He is himself once again, in every way.
事实上  只要伍尔希先生一回到代达罗斯号
In fact, I'm going to request that
我就去请求让迦楠还有其他人
he and many of the others be allowed to return to the city,
重返城市生活
as soon as mr.Woolsey arrives in the daedalus.
我仍然不敢相信山姆竟然不回来
I still can't believe sam's not coming back.
这比较艰难
It is difficult.
不管怎么说
Well, anyway,
加南还有其他混合人不是我治好的
it wasn't me that cured kanaan and the other hybrids.
全是贝克特医生的逆转录酶的功劳
It was dr.Beckett's retrovirus,
如果我能搞明白幽灵族的医疗资料
and you could thank him in person if I could just
你就可以亲自感谢他
get my head around all this wraith medical data.
你认为答案就在这其中
You believe the answer's in there somewhere?
我们知道他给卡森注射血清
We know he was giving carson a serum
能防止他体内器官的衰老
to keep his internal organs from deteriorating,
我想我可能找到配方了
and I think I might have found the formula
只是要更加确认
I just need to be sure.
至少我们知道他现在很安全
Well, at least we know he's safe for the moment.
理论上讲  是的
Technically, yeah.
一想到他被关在笼子里  我就揪心
I just hate the thought of him being stuck in that box.
你知道罗德尼去看过他吗
You know rodney goes to visit him?
他就这么站在静止分离舱前
He stands in front of the stasis pod
和他讲最近的事情
and tells him all the latest news.
真的
Really?
一次我偶然进门撞见他
I walked in on him once by accident,
他马上假装自己在检查系统什么的
and he pretended like he was checking the system or something.
他有时总给我惊喜
He surprises me sometimes.
我又要去成为忙碌的妈妈了
Well, this is me once again being recalled to duty.
一路慢走
Have a nice walk.
詹妮弗  别担心
Don't worry, jennifer.
我相信一定会有痊愈的方法的
I'm sure you'll find what you're looking for.
长官  代达罗斯号刚脱离了超空间带
Sir, daedalus just dropped out of hyperspace.
我们收到一个信号
We're receiving a signal.
他来了
He's coming down.
伍尔希长官  欢迎回来
Mr. Woolsey, welcome back.
谢谢上校
Thank you, colonel.
我想我还是从看你们全体人员的
I think I'll start by going over
最新报告开始吧
copies of all your latest reports.
你的也要  博士
Yours as well, doctor.
现在就看?
What, right now?
我已经有3个星期没联系代达罗斯号了
I've been out of touch on the daedalus for three weeks.
我要以最快的速度使一切正常运行
I'd like to be brought up to speed as quickly as possible.
早上我们来开个重要会议
We can have a full briefing in the morning.
请把我的用品直接送到我的住处
Please have the rest of my things sent directly to my quarters.
好的  长官
Yes, sir.
多好的发言词
Nice speech.
真振奋人心
Very inspiring.
好吧  我们再做一次
All right, let's do one more series,
看看结论能不能标准化一点
see if we can get the results to normalize a little.
医生  你还在这里
Doctor, you're still here.
我在桌上睡着了
Oh, yeah, I fell asleep at my desk.
希望你要不介意
Well, if you don't mind me saying,
不过我觉得你对自己太苛刻了
I think you're pushing yourself a little hard.
放松点吧
You should take it easy.
我知道  我这就去睡觉
I know, I'M... going to turn in now.
你还好吧
Are you all right?
我没事
Yeah, I'm fine.
那就好  晚安
Okay, 'night.
晚安
'Night.
你昨晚睡了吗
did you get any sleep last night?
我脸色不好么
Do I really look that bad?
当然不是这个意思
No, no, of course not. That's not what I meant.
看起来很好啊
Uh, it's really... it's a lovely...
谢谢
thanks.
新桌子  不错啊
Wow, new table, huh?
是伍尔希带过来的
Woolsey brought it with him.
他说这样有家的感觉
He said he wanted a little piece of home.
3.6米长红木会议桌
A 12-foot-long mahogany conference table, hmm...
我不明白
I don't get it.
我认为卡特上校工作很出色
I thought colonel carter was doing a good job.
我也这么认为
I agree.
我们打败了复制人  阻止了迈克尔的阴谋
We defeated the replicators, we thwarted michael's plans,
现在幽灵们都溃不成军了
the wraith are in a state of disarray.
这些都是在她的领导下取得的成就
All this happened while she was leader of atlantis.
这就是问题所在
That's the problem.
我不明白
I don't understand.
她的成功把自己害了
She's a victim of her own success.
现在威胁等级下降
Now that the threat level is down,
组织就抓住这个机会
the ioa's going to jump at the chance
派个文职官员回来
to put a civilian back in command.
还不仅仅是这样
Well, it's not just that.
山姆不那么拘泥于规矩
I mean, sam didn't exactly stick to protocol.
韦尔也是
Neither did weir.
所以他们等了4年
Right, so for four years, they've been waiting
终于找到个替他们办事的人来了
to get someone in there who'll finally do things their way.
我还是不明白
I still don't get it.
上校  你身处未来时空
Colonel, when you were in the future,
就可以知道现在即将发生的一切
and you learned all those things that were going to happen,
伍尔希掌权这事不也是其中之一吗
wasn't this one of them, woolsey taking over?
情况有点不太一样
Well, the circumstances were different.
还真是混乱啊
Still, it is a little unsettling.
我是说  也许要改变事态的发生
I mean, maybe it's harder to
比我们想象的要困难
change the course of events than we thought.
这我倒不担心
Well, I wouldn't worry about it.
现在谢帕德回来了
I mean, the fact that sheppard's here
事情都改观了  不是吗
makes all the difference, right?
那点时间线上伍尔希的事不是最可怕的
Woolsey wasn't the weirdest thing about that timeline.
什么意思
What do you mean?
没什么
Never mind.
大家都到齐了
I see everyone's here.
就开始吧
Let's get started.
首先要祝贺你们全体人员
first of all, I'd like to congratulate all of you
在捣毁迈克尔遗留组织行动中
on the success you've had dismantling
取得了佳绩
what's left of michael's organization.
除了我们还没找到迈克尔尸首
Except one thing. We haven't found him yet.
你们在太空轨道m2s 445附近
Well, he was on the cruiser
击落了他乘坐的飞船
you destroyed in orbit around m2s 445.
他有可能逃离了那艘飞船
There's a chance he may have made it off the ship.
很对  你的这个意见在
Right, you're referring to this statement given by
一个迈克尔旧部的报告中提及
one of michael's ex-mercenaries,
声称有人看见他还活着
claiming to have seen him alive recently.
这就是他说的
That's what he said.
这个未经证实的情报来源
This is one unsubstantiated report
是毫无根据的
from a highly unreliable source.
但是有人从那艘飞船上偷走了我们的战机
Well, someone stole our jumper off that ship.
需要古人DNA才能开走那些战机吧
I thought you needed ancient dna to pilot one of those.
没这个必要  我们发明的基因疗法
Not necessarily. We developed a gene therapy that works...
有时就可以行的通
some of the time.
他要为成千上万人
He is responsible for the deaths
的死亡负责
of hundreds of thousands of people.
如果他还活着  即使可能性很小
If there is even a chance that he is still alive,
我们也一定要继续搜寻
we must continue the search.
抱歉  我不能耗费
I'm sorry, but I can't devote
全部人力在全宇宙
the resources of this base to the never-ending
毫无止境的搜寻一个人
pursuit of a single individual across an entire galaxy.
即使我知道他还活着
Even if I knew for a fact he were still alive,
我也不会下令搜寻
I still wouldn't authorize it, unless you have
除非你们有他藏身点的可靠证据
some new, credible evidence as to his whereabouts.
你们有吗
Do you?
没有
No.
那么眼下
Then, for the time being,
这件事就先搁着
I shall consider the matter closed.
至于那些混合人
As to these prisoner hybrids.
据我所知  他们被关在大陆的的拘留营中
I understand they're being held in a camp on the mainland?
没错
That's right.
他们的康复计划进展地怎么样了
And how is their rehabilitation progressing?
医生?
Doctor?
我们取得了一定成果
well, um, we've had some success
利用早期创造迈克尔的逆转录酶
using a slightly modified version of the original retrovirus
来进行少许改良
that created michael in the first place.
并筛除幽灵的DNA
It weeds out the wraith dna,
这样就可以重新恢复他们的人类形态
and allows them to resume their original human form, over time.
会不会有长期副作用
Without any lasting ill effects?
目前还没有
None that we've detected so far.
很多人已经完成了治疗计划
Many have already completed the treatment.
他们想知道什么时候可以重享自由
They're wondering when they might be released.
别急  一件件来
Let's not get ahead of ourselves.
伍尔希长官  这些人是受害者
These people are victims, mr. Woolsey.
也许是  但起码现在
Maybe so, but until very recently,
他们还是敌人
they were also enemy combatants.
好吧  那我们就把他们终身监禁
Fine. We'll just keep them there forever.
不  直到我认为他们可以被信任时
No. We'll keep them there
他们就成恢复自由之身
until I'm satisfied that they can be trusted.
至于那个被关在静止分离舱里的朋友
Now, regarding the situation with our friend in the stasis pod.
最近你好像对他
You seem to have been giving
非常关注啊
a significant amount of attention to this lately.
自从我们得到迈克尔的医疗研究
Well, once we got our hands on michael's medical research,
我就想第一时间研究出解决方案
I thought I should make it a priority to look for a solution.
你得出结果了?
And have you found one?
有点
Maybe.
我们发现一种血清
We found a serum that,
可以在实验室里
in lab tests at least,
稳定克隆细胞
seems to be capable of stabilizing the clone cells.
那有什么问题呢
So, what's the problem?
实验一度危及其到卡森的生命
Carson was near death when we put him in that chamber.
我要在百分百确定的情况下再进行测试
I don't want to take him out until I know for sure,
但现在实验室进展就只能到这里
but lab tests can only do so much.
但这问题并不会就此消失  对吧
But that problem's never going to go away, is it?
如果你的研究达到了极限
If you've reached the limit of what your research can tell you,
你就需要做出决定
then you need to make a decision.
要么就继续  别管其副作用
Either proceed, or put the matter aside
要么就回到你的本职工作
and get back to your regular duty.
对吗
Right?
你确定吗
You sure about this?
不  但是我们不试试的话就永远得不出结论
No, but we're never going to be sure unless we give it a shot.
他也就会永远禁锢在这里
If we don't take a chance now, he could be in there forever.
好吧
All right, then.
把他扶到担架上
Get him on the gurney.
小心
Careful...
好了
okay.
现在怎么办
Now what?
现在我们带他去医务室
Now we take him to the infirmary
进一步观察有无细胞退化现象
and watch for signs for more cellular degradation.
很快就可以知道结果了
We should know soon enough.
嗨
Hey there.
感觉如何
How you doing?
还好
Fine.
出了什么事
What happened?
你以为呢
Well, what do you think?
我们把你解冻了
We thawed you out.
还能见到你真好  卡森
It's nice to see you again, carson.
是啊感觉怎样  医生  好久不见了
Yeah, what's up, doc? It's been a while.
没错
Aye.
我在那呆了多久
How long was I in there?
差不多2个月
Two months, give or take.
这期间有什么大事发生吗
Did I miss anything?
没什么  像平常一样
You know, just the usual.
我有个好消息
Well, I've got good news.
目前  你还没有出现细胞退化现象
At the moment, you're showing no signs of cellular degradation.
那你的工作就轻松多了
You were able to recreate the treatment.
没错
That's right.
我会让他们把一切都告诉你
I'll let them tell you all about it.
医生...干的不错
Hey, doc... um, nice work.
但这不是长久之计
Well, it's not a permanent solution.
当前来说已经足够了
It's good enough for now.
休息下吧
Go get some rest.
对  我觉得这是个好主意
Yeah, I think that might be a good idea.
你在这
There you are.
太美了  是不是
Gorgeous, isn't it?
是吧
I suppose so.
你知道吗  我以前真的很留恋这地方
You know, I really did miss this place.
是啊  不过别总想这些了
Yeah, well, don't get used to it.
这什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
听着  我刚得知他们要送你回地球
Look, I just found out they're sending you back to earth.
下午会有一次预定拨号
There's a scheduled dial-out this afternoon.
我想这也是应该的吧
Oh, well, I suppose it's to be expected.
我是说  即使接受这些治疗
I mean, even with these injections,
想要完全恢复
I imagine it'd still be months
也要数月之久
before I'm in any sort of decent physical condition.
罗德尼  我是泰勒  麻烦过来一下
Rodney, this is teyla, come in, please.
什么事
Go ahead.
很抱歉打扰你  但我需要你的帮助
I'm sorry to bother you, but I need your help.
怎么了
What is it?
是凯勒医生  本来我们说好一起吃早饭的
It's dr.Keller. She was supposed join me for breakfast this morning
但现在还没过来
but did not show up.
也许她还在睡觉
So maybe she's sleeping in.
我开始也这么想  决定不打扰她
I assumed as much as well, and decided not to disturb her.
可是已经过了4个小时了
However, that was four hours ago.
她现在值班都晚了
She's now late for her shift,
而且呼叫她也没有回应
and she's not responding to radio calls.
你想要我怎么做
What do you want me to do about it?
破坏门控
Override the door controlS.
我不会破门而入的
I'm not breaking into her room.
罗德尼  也许有异常情况
Rodney, there might be something wrong.
好吧  但如果她只是在那睡觉
Fine, but if she's just in there sleeping,
裸体或是什么  你们得承担责任
or naked or something, you guys are taking the blame.
天啊  罗德尼  快点吧
oh, for god's sake, rodney, hurry up.
珍妮弗  你没事吧
Jennifer, are you all right?
珍妮弗
Jennifer?
她肯定昏迷了
She must be unconscious.
瞳孔放大
Pupils dilated.
卡森  退后
Carson, step away from the bed.
怎么了
What?
快点退后
Step away now!
怎么回事
What is it?
天啊
Dear lord.
谢帕德上校  我是泰勒
Colonel sheppard, this is teyla.
请说
Go ahead.
约翰  我们有麻烦
John, we have a problem.
到底怎么了
What the hell's going on?
我们不能确定  发现她的时候就这样了
We're not sure. This is how we found her.
肯定昨晚发生的
It must've happened last night.
我以前见过这种东西
I've seen something like this before.
在哪
Where?
迈克尔的一个实验室里
One of michael's labs.
他当时在进行一些实验
He was conducting some kind of experiment.
我们得把这东西弄开
Well, we've got to get it off of her.
我不觉得这是个好主意
I'm not so certain that's such a good idea.
依我看
From what I can tell,
她和床架还有这些须蔓已经连为一体了
the tendrils are attached to her and the bedframe.
如果我们硬扯下来
If we just start ripping them off,
会让她受重伤的
we could cause her serious injury.
但我们不能就这样让她躺在这
Well, we can't just leave her like this.
我们得把她弄到隔离室
We need to get her into an isolation chamber,
连床一起
and take the whole bed as well.
那样我们才能进行全面检查
That way we can run a full examination
看看到底出了什么状况
and see what we're dealing with here.
那些东西是从她体内长出来的?
These things are actually growing out of her body?
看起来像是
That's what it looks like.
她还有意识吗
Is she conscious?
贝克特说她的脑活跃度
Beckett says her brain activity
与普通的昏迷病人类似
is consistent with somebody in a coma.
贝克特医生还没有复职啊
Dr. Beckett is not on active duty.
他当时在现场
He was the first one there.
说他以前见过类似的东西
He says he's seen something like this before.
当他被监禁的时候
While he was a prisoner.
他被迫为迈克尔工作了2年
He was forced to work for michael for two years.
没有人比他更了解这东西了
Nobody knows this stuff better than he does.
我先试着切断较细的须蔓
I'm going to try to cut some of the thinner strands.
手术刀
Scalpel.
谢谢
Thank you.
好了
There we go.
护士?
Nurse?
一切正常
No change.
马上拿去化验
Get that analyzed right away.
医生  血压在下降  脉搏也是
Doctor, blood pressure's dropping. Pulse as well.
我就担心这种情况  她的生命力在下降
That's what I was afraid of. She's crashing.
注入5毫克阿托品
Administer five milligrams of atropine.
天啊...
My god...
加油...
come on...
好了
there she is.
抱歉  我不敢再切了
I'm sorry, I don't dare make another incision.
看来不能动其它的了
So much for cutting her loose.
贝克特医生  我想和你谈谈
Dr. Beckett, I'd like a word.
别担心  我会救她出来  只要我回到实验室
Don't worry, I'll get her out. Once I get back to the lab--
医生  我很感激你的努力
doctor, I appreciate what you're trying to do,
但到地球的拨号1小时后就开始了
but our earth dial-out is in one hour.
如果你不介意  我想等下一次再走
I'll take a pass on this one, if you don't mind.
如果不是凯勒医生
If it wasn't for dr. Keller,
我可能还被关在静室里  甚至永远关在那
I'd still be locked in that stasis chamber, possibly forever.
凯勒医生的报告十分清楚
Dr. Keller's own report is abundantly clear.
即使你的病情稳定了
While your condition has stabilized,
你的内脏依然受损严重
you've still suffered severe damage to your internal organs.
你需要在医院静养
You need to be in a hospital bed yourself,
而不是去操刀手术
not running a medical investigation.
我没事
I'll be fine.
一发现身体不适  我会立刻退让  我保证
At the first sign of trouble, I'll step aside, I promise.
你确信这与迈克尔有关?
You're convinced this has something to do with michael?
这可不是什么麻疹  对不对
Well, it's not a case of the hives, is it?
她怎么样了
How's she doing?
基本稳定了  依然还有微弱脑电波
Vitals have stabilized, still showing minimal brain function.
我们已取得血液和组织样本
We did manage to get blood and tissue samples.
好吧  那我们有活要做了
All right, then we've got some work to do.
你不是要把他送回去吗
You're not sending him back, huh?
他是这方面唯一的专家了
He is the closest thing to an expert we have.
这可不是照章办事
It's not exactly by the book.
别老是这样
Don't get used to it.
进展如何
How's it coming?
缓慢
Slowly,
但我在珍妮弗的血样里发现了些东西
but I did find something in jennifer's blood sample.
什么
What?
别急
Easy.
是某种外星病菌  从未见过
It's some kind of alien pathogen, so far unidentified.
我正在对照数据库
I'm checking it against the database.
她会不会变成混种人
Is it possible she's turning into a hybrid?
不  我想不会
No, I don't think so.
我见过很多变种的实例
I've seen several variations of the conversion process,
从来没有这样的
but never anything like this.
这肯定与迈克尔有关
Well, it's got to be something to do with michael.
我是说  她把我们救出实验室后
I mean, she hasn't been offworld
就再没出去过
since she helped rescue us from that lab.
我也这么想
That's what I was thinking.
当然  如果她是
Of course, if that's
在那里感染上病菌的话...
where she came in contact with the pathogen...
你认为我们也有可能被感染了
you think the rest of us may have been exposed as well.
是啊  这很有可能
Well, aye, it's a possibility.
我需要当时在场的所有人的血样
I'll need blood samples from everyone who was on that planet,
包括你
including you.
很好
Oh, great.
医生...
Doctor...
什么事
Yes?
说
Yes.
她醒了
She's awake.
谢谢  好的
Thank you. Right.
天啊...
Oh, my god...
罗德尼  我这是怎么了
rodney, what's happening to me?
我们还不十分肯定
We're not entirely sure.
这像是某种茧
It looks like some kind of a cocoon.
疼吗
Does it hurt?
我什么也感觉不到  完全动不了
I can't feel anything. I can't move.
好吧  听着...
Okay, look...
你不要担心  好吗  我们会把你救出来
don't you worry, okay? We're going to get you out.
还有谁在这
Who else is here?
什么意思  没别人了
What do you mean? There's no one.
我不想睡觉  我怕再也不会醒来
I don't want to go to sleep. I'm afraid I won't wake up.
珍妮弗
Jennifer?
不是我的错
It's not my fault.
当然不是  这是某种外星生物
Of course it's not. It's an alien organism.
什么
What?
卡森在你血样里发现的
Carson found it in your blood sample.
他正在研究这东西的  然后
He's going to figure out what it is, and then
我们就知道如何消灭它了
we're going to figure out how to kill it.
我的手
My hand.
怎么了
What about it?
是从手开始的
That's where it started.
我几天前看到的
I saw it a few nights ago.
那你当时为什么不说
So why didn't you say anything?
我当时在扫描  我...
I was going to run a scan. I don'T...
我不知道
I don't know.
没关系  知道吗  我们会搞定的
It doesn't matter, okay? We're going to fix this.
我保证
I promise.
这东西似乎能影响她的意识
It appears to be affecting her mind.
是啊  她说能听到些声音
Aye, she claims to be hearing voices,
好像房间里还有其他人
like there's someone else in the room with her.
它生长的有多快
How fast is it growing?
目前来看  每过几小时就会增殖一倍
Currently, it's doubling its mass every couple of hours.
谢谢
Thank you.
这已经不仅仅关系到凯勒医生了
This isn't just about dr. Keller anymore.
我得知道这东西
I need to know if this thing
是否会威胁到基地的安全
is going to be a threat to the base.
答案是肯定的
I'd say that's a definite yes.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
谢帕德上校  若楠  罗德尼
Colonel sheppard, ronon, rodney,
所有到过m2s 445的人
everyone who was on m2s 445,
检验结果全部为阳性
they all tested positive.
不管这到底是什么
Whatever this is,
他们都感染了
they've all got it.
现在我们假定
Right now we're working under the assumption
这个外星病毒源于那个实验室
that this alien pathogen was present somewhere in that lab,
很可能是迈克尔实验的一部分
possibly as part of one of michael's experiments.
那所建筑被毁的时候  它随之释放出来
When the building was destroyed, it was released.
我们已经回来一个多月
We've been back for a month now.
如果它要大面积传播的话
It was going to spread to the general population,
现在早就大爆发了
it would've already happened.
我知道
I know.
贝克特医生确认它是无传染性的
Dr. Beckett is now fairly confident that it's not contagious.
那为什么要我们只能呆在房间里
Right, then, why confine us to our quarters?
你也看过凯勒医生的症状
You've seen what's happening to dr. Keller.
-没错 但我可没那样啊  -还没有而已
- Yeah, but it's not happening to me.  -Not yet.
症状先从凯勒医生开始
There could be any number of random physiological
可能有很多随机的生理因素
reasons why it's starting with dr. Keller,
但现在不能保证
but that's no guarantee that
你们不会发生这种情况
it's not going to happen to the rest of you.
可能再过几天  甚至几小时
It could be a matter of days, it could be a matter of hours.
就连卡特上校返回星门指挥部也要被隔离
Even colonel carter's been quarantined back at stargate command.
听着  我知道对你来说
Look, I know it's hard for you
当一个旁观者很难受  上校
to stay on the sidelines, colonel,
但这才是正确的做法
but it's the right call.
那这个时候凯勒怎么办
In the meantime, what are we going to do about keller?
我们还在研究当前形势
We're still assessing the situation.
我们还不知道病毒
We still don't know how the pathogen
如何引起了生理变化
causes the physiological changes,
但已经完成了
but we've managed to
对萃取样品的分析
complete our analysis of the sample I extracted.
本质上这是一种二元共聚物
Essentially it's a biopolymer,
类似于多糖类
similar to a polysaccharide,
但是混合了有机金属
but with organo-metallic compounds mixed in.
请通俗点  医生
For the uninitiated, please, doctor.
就像是昆虫或者甲壳类生物
It's like the material
构成其外壳的物质
an insect or a crustacean uses to form its shell.
刚开始很柔软
At first, it's soft and pliable,
随后变得极为坚硬
and then it becomes tough and leathery,
最后会到达一种不可思议的密度
and eventually it hardens into an incredible density,
能抵御热能  压力甚至辐射
resistant to heat, pressure, and even radiation.
是的  就像飞船的外壳
Yes, it's like the hull of a ship.
是的
Aye.
你在说什么
What are you saying?
听着  我们知道幽灵战舰本身是生物体
Look, we always knew that the wraith ships were organic in design,
本质上说  它不是被建造的而是自己长成的
right, that they were essentially grown instead of constructed.
我们只是从没看到过而已
We've just never witnessed it before.
你是在告诉我说
Are you telling me that
隔离室内部会长出一艘蜂巢式战舰?
a hive ship is growing inside that isolation room?
事实上它已经不算是在隔离室内部了
Actually, it's no longer just inside the isolation room.
生命探测器发现不了它
It doesn't register on our life-signs detector,
但一旦我们知道要找的是什么
but once we knew what we were looking for,
就可以校准内部传感器来提取信号
we calibrated our internal sensors to pick it up.
它已经穿过了墙面和地板
It has penetrated the walls and the floors,
消耗和转化它所经过的物质
consuming and converting the material as it goes.
传播的有多快
How far has it spread?
已经向下延伸了3层
It's gone down... three levels already,
而且它黏附到电力系统去了
and it has attached itself to the electrical system.
它正在吸取电能
It's siphoning off power as it goes.
好像这还能显著加快它的生长速度
This seems to have accelerated its growth significantly.
怎样才能阻止它
How do we stop it?
这是我们正在研究的
That's the part we're still trying to figure out.
我们可以切断电源
We could cut off the power.
这能大大降低它的增长速度
That should slow it down quite a bit.
怎么回事
What's happening?
玛丽  怎么回事
Marie, what's going on?
医生  我们被要求立即撤离这里
Doctor, we've been ordered to evacuate the building.
对不起
I'm sorry.
他们就这样抛弃她了?
They just left her there?
他们别无选择啊
I don't think they had much of a choice.
卡森正在搜索迈克尔的数据库
Carson is searching michael's database
看看有没有可以帮助我们的东西
to see if there is anything that can help us.
关掉电源是泽兰卡的主意吧
I suppose it was zelenka's idea to shut off the power?
不清楚  怎么了
I don't know. Why?
这太荒唐了
This is ridiculous.
新来的家伙采纳了二队的建议
They got us stuck in our quarters
而把我们隔离了?
while the new guy takes advice from the b team?
什么意思  罗德尼
What is it, rodney?
他们认为这东西穿透了墙壁地面
They are assuming that it tapped into the electric grid
然后接入了电力网
by randomly spreading out through the walls and floors.
如果它实际上是向电磁场生长呢
What if it actually grows towards electromagnetic fields,
就像植物向阳生长
like a plant growing toward the sun?
它会直接向下一个合适的能源延伸
It's going to head directly for the next available power source.
这里
There.
城市下面的某个主电力通道
One of the city's main power conduits runs beneath the building.
这么说那个区域的电源也得关掉
So shut the power down in that section as well.
不  我们已经做了
No, we already did, right,
不过这条线缆直接跟零点通道相连
but this runs directly into the zpm.
就好比是快行道
It's like an express lane.
我们已经关闭了剩下的通道  但是
We've already shut off the rest of the traffic, but
这一条还会独立运作
this one keeps moving along.
唯一能阻止它的办法就是拔出零点通道
The only way to stop it would be to pull the zpm
然后关掉整个城市的电力
and shut off power to the entire city.
想不到你对配电网
I had no idea you were so familiar
会这么熟悉
with the power distribution grid.
没有啦  我只是和罗德尼谈过
I'm not. I spoke to rodney.
这有问题吗
Is there a problem?
病原体似乎对寄主有心理上的影响
The pathogen seems to have a psychological effect on the host.
至少我们知道在出现生理症状前
At the very least, we know it can affect their judgment,
大脑的思维能力就会被影响
possibly well before any physical symptoms appear.
是的  但他这一点说得没错
Yes, but he's not wrong about this.
如果它到达输电管
If it reaches the conduit,
就可以无限制的获取电能了
it will have access to virtually unlimited power.
然后会怎样
And what would happen?
生长速度会呈指数级别增长
The growth would increase exponentially.
而我们因为关掉这部分的电源
And since we've shut this section down,
就没有任何传感器了
we have no sensors in the area,
所以只能用肉眼
so the only way to know how far it's penetrated is
观察它的延伸范围了
to do a visual inspection.
好吧  全体集合
All right, assemble a team.
我需要答案  医生
I need some answers, doctor.
怎么把这东西弄死
How do we kill this thing?
我们在研究一种遗传病毒
Well, we're working on a genetically engineered virus
也许可以消灭
that might be capable of destroying the pathogen
感染凯勒医生的病原体
that's infecting dr. Keller
但不会根除这种高分子聚合物
but that wouldn't eliminate the biopolymer itself.
怎么才行
What would?
伍尔希先生  现在我也不知道
At this time, mr. Woolsey, I have no idea.
主电力通道从这堵墙后穿过
So the main conduit runs behind this wall here.
这里  我们可以通过这个面板进去
Here, we can access it through this panel.
警官  带上你的人  分头行动
Sergeant, take your men, split up,
搜索周围走廊
and search the surrounding corridors.
检查下有没有什么异常
Look for anything that seems unusual.
好了吗
All right?
好了
Okay.
我去那边
Right, I'll go this way.
保持通信联络
Stay in radio contact.
我想我找到了些东西
I think I have something.
看起来罗德尼是对的
Looks like rodney was right.
天啊
Oh my.
怎么了
What is it?
看来它已经黏附上电力管了
Looks like it's attached itself to the power conduit.
我过来找你
I'm coming to you.
我看看能否测定
I'm going to see if I can determine
它吸取了多少能量
how much power it's draining.
快走  快走
Let's go, let's go.
快点
Come on.
你还好吗
Are you all right?
还行
I think so.
这比我们预料到的要糟多了
This is much worse than we thought.
-我不知道它还可以动  -我也是
-I had no idea it could move like that.  -Nor did I.
看起来只是轻微的脑震荡  没什么事的
looks like it's just a minor concussion. He should be fine.
看来让这东西
So it wasn't bad enough
逐渐占领基地还不是最糟的
that this thing was slowly taking over the base.
现在它开始攻击人了?
Now it's attacking people?
我们需要想出一个解决办法
We need to put a stop to this, now.
有难度啊
It won't be easy.
它已经吸收了大量能量
It's already siphoned off a massive amount of power.
我们应该拔出零点通道
We should pull the zpm.
这样还不行
That might not be enough.
我们在黑暗中呆坐数周
We could sit here in the dark for weeks
而这东西则会不断生长
while it just keeps on growing.
我们得把珍妮弗弄出这儿
We need to get jennifer out of there.
我和各位一样想救凯勒的命
I want to save dr. Keller as much as anyone else,
但是我们有其他东西需要考虑
but we have additional concerns now.
为什么它会攻击拉迪克
Why did it attack radek?
因为它认为他会对自己造成威胁
Because it perceived him as a threat and took action.
这说明它有智慧
That indicates intelligence,
但就我们所知  但它并没有自己的大脑
but as far as we know, it has no brain of its own.
你的意思是它在利用她
So you're saying it's using her.
它是需要她
I'm saying it needs her,
来计划  调整  识别威胁  并作出反应
to plan, to coordinate, to identify threats and deal with them.
难怪她说会听到一些声音
That could explain why she was hearing voices.
这种生物体会部分占据她的大脑
The organism takes over a portion of the brain,
建立一个独立的意识
and sets up a separate consciousness.
就像是多种人格一样
Like multiple personalities.
这就是要找个人作为寄主的原因
Otherwise, why have a human host at all?
这么说只要我们把它跟寄主分开
So if we separate her from the main body...
我保证剩下的部分
I'd wager the rest of it
就跟老树根一样毫无活力了
becomes as lifeless as a dead tree trunk.
这就是我刚才所说的病毒
Now, this is the virus I was telling you about.
这是一种噬菌体
It's called a phage,
至少从理论上说  它可以攻击并消灭
and it should, at least theoretically, be able to attack and eliminate
珍妮弗血液中的病菌
the pathogen that's inside jennifer's bloodstream,
如果我没猜错的话
and if I'm right about this,
它将切断它们之间的连接
it should sever the connection.
但是?
What's the catch?
还没有经过测试
Well, it's never been tested.
我们暂时恢复一下能量供应
We turned the power back on briefly
看看情况如何
to get a look inside the building.
这是底层
This is the ground floor,
跟隔离室相隔5层
five floors below the isolation room.
如你所看到的  通道几乎全被堵死了
As you can see, access is almost completely choked off,
但想要实施我们的计划  得有人
but for this to work, I need someone
走到凯勒床边帮她注射
to step right up to dr. Keller's bed and inject her.
可以通过传送机前往比较靠近的地方  不过
Well, we can use the transporter to get them close, but--
但还要在荆棘中行进至少50米
but you'd still have to run a gauntlet of over 50 meters.
而且在泽兰卡博士那件事以后
And after what happened to dr. Zelenka...
你们应该明白我现在的困境
well, you understand my dilemma.
是啊
Yeah.
什么
What?
如果凯勒真的是这场危机的关键
If dr. Keller really is the key to this thing,
有个更简单的方法
there is an easier way.
我们只需朝隔离室
We'd only need a couple of well-aimed shots
开几炮就行了
at the isolation room.
等等  你指用飞弹?
Wait a second, you're talking about drones?
你要朝我们自己人发射飞弹?
You're going to fire drones at one of our own people?
我也不想一来亚特兰蒂斯
I didn't come to atlantis with the intention of
就牺牲手下的资深队员
killing one of my senior staff inside of a week,
但不那样的话
but my only other option
就要让其他人冒生命的危险...
is to risk someone else's life on a solution...
而且这种方案还没有经过测试
that hasn't even been tested yet.
按照规定这是不行的
Not exactly by the book.
那就测试吧
So test it.
我体内也有那种东西
I've got the same bug.
现在就给我注射吧
I'll take a shot right now.
不  不  不
No, no, no...
我来
I'll do it.
束缚带?
Restraints, huh?
抱歉  不过你可能会有强烈反应
I'm sorry, but I'm anticipating a severe reaction.
太好了
Oh, great.
你真的确定要这么做?
Now, you're absolutely sure about this?
要知道  这可是迈克尔提供的配方
Remember, the formula comes from michael,
就我们所知  这可能
so as far all we know, it could-
把我变成虫子?
turn me into a bug?
又不是第一次了  来吧
Been there, done that.
不  事实上  我是说
No, actually, I was going to say
可能会让你送命
it could kill you.
好了...给我打针吧
Just... give me the shot.
好吧
Okay.
药剂需要几分钟时间起效  所以...
Now, it should take a few minutes to kick in, so just...
-放轻松  -好  我会...
- Try to relax. - Oh, okay, I'll just...
我会放松的
I'll relax.
卡森  罗恩和其他人已经有病症了
Carson, is it true that Lorne and some of the others
是不是真的
are beginning to show symptoms?
我想是的
Aye, I'm afraid so.
天啊...
Oh, god...
为什么
why?
你觉得自己有什么不对劲的
Have you noticed something yourself?
我老是手心出汗
Well, my palms are very sweaty,
还有口干舌燥
and my mouth is very dry,
心跳也很快
I'm having heart palpitations.
这些都很正常  还有吗?
Okay, so, nothing out of the ordinary, then?
感觉怎么样
How do you feel?
没什么感觉
I don't feel anything.
我甚至觉得...
I don't even think that...
谢帕德?
Sheppard?
博士...
Hey, doc...
我想这抑制剂真是个好东西
I think these restraints were a good idea.
它起作用了
It's working.
情况怎么样
What's our status?
包括医疗室在内的主要系统
Well, the infirmary, and a few other essential systems
已经启用应急发电设备
have been switched to emergency generators.
都准备好了
We're ready.
好了  拔掉总闸
All right, pull the plug.
看在上帝的份上  卡森
For god's sake, Carson,
这要多久
how long's this going to go on for?
抱歉  罗德尼  我也不知道
I'm sorry, Rodney, I have no idea.
博士...
Doc...
他心跳停了  给他呼吸罩
His heart stopped. Bag him.
把手术推车拿过来
Get a crash cart in here!
准备好插管
Prepare to intubate.
1，2，3
One, two, three.
挺住
Come on.
1，2，3
One, two, three.
又有心跳了
He's back.
我怎么样了
How'd I do?
你确定起作用了吗
Are you sure it worked?
血检显示为阴性
Well, the blood screen came up negative.
要我说
As far as I can tell,
外星病毒已经清除了
the alien pathogen has been eliminated.
做得好
Well done.
现在我们要派个人去隔离室
Now we just need someone to go to the isolation room.
-我去...  -我去
- I'll do it--  - I'll do it.
我想使用这药剂
I assume no special medical skill is required
不需要什么专业医疗技术吧
to administer the drug.
不需要  就是一个简单的注射
Well, no, not really. It's just a simple injection.
那就现在的情况看
Well, then, given your condition,
我是不会选你去的
I wouldn't make you my first choice.
所以说了我去
That's why I said I'd do it.
他不信任我们
He doesn't trust us,
因为我们也被感染了
because we're still infected.
其实这样也没什么不好
Actually, that might not be a bad thing.
谢帕德上校曾感染过伊瑞特斯虫的DNA
When Colonel Sheppard was infected with iratus bug dna,
然后他就畅通无阻地进入巢穴
he was able to walk right into that nest
不受到任何攻击
without being attacked.
你是说感染病毒的人
You think someone infected with the pathogen
反而更容易通过?
would be more likely to get through?
很可能
Well, it's possible.
好了  我进来了
All right, I'm in.
切断运输机电源
Cut power to the transporter.
情况怎么样
How does it look?
不怎么样
Not so good.
那鬼东西到处都是
The stuff's everywhere.
他对你有没有什么反应
Is it reacting to your presence in any way?
没看出来
Not really.
好吧  那...
All right, just...
小心
be careful.
发生了什么
What happened?
药起作用了
It worked.
他们派若楠去给她打一针
They just sent Ronon to give her the shot.
什么时候
When?
他刚到那儿
He just got there. Look.
我接入了通讯系统
I'm tapped into the intercom.
若楠  情况怎样?
Ronon, what's your status?
越来越难走了
Well, it's getting harder to move.
这到处都是
There's too much of it.
尽量缓慢移动
Just... try not to make any sudden moves, or...
不要有威胁性动作
threatening gestures.
好的  我会记住的
Yeah, I'll keep that in mind.
好了
All right,
到了
that's it.
我不能再靠近了
I don't think I can go any further.
走廊都被堵住了
The corridor is completely blocked.
好了  你们要我怎么做?
All right, so what do you want me to do?
-管它了  先弄个洞  -等等  若楠
- Screw it, I'm going to make a hole.  - Ronon, wait!
你能走到那么远
The only reason you made it this far
只是因为它感觉到了你血液里的病毒
is because it senses the pathogen in your bloodstream.
它认为你是同伴
It thinks you're a friend.
如果你开枪...
If you start shooting--
还有谁有更好的点子?
Does anyone have any better ideas?
你在干嘛?
What are you doing?
如果我想得没错
If I'm right,
我们犯了个大错误
this is about to go very, very wrong.
你不能去
You can't.
- 我们被隔离了  - 你忘了我已经好了?
- We're quarantined-- - I'm cured, remember?
没有其他路可以走了
There's no other way through.
一旦你开了枪
Once you start shooting,
要马上离开
you'll have to move quickly.
谢谢提醒
Thanks for the advice.
若楠?
Ronon?
若楠  你怎么样了
Ronon, what's your status?
若楠  快回答
Ronon, come in!
天啊...
Oh, my god...
现在什么情况
What's happening?
我们失去联系了
We've lost contact.
重启电源
Turn the power back on.
开通隔离室的通讯频道
Open up a channel to the isolation room.
什么  为什么
What? Why?
只管照做
Just do it.
好了  频道通了
All right, you have a channel.
凯勒博士  我是谢帕德上校  听得到吗
Dr. Keller, this is Colonel Sheppard, do you read?
我能听到  上校  但我不是凯勒博士
I hear you, Colonel, but I'm not Dr. Keller anymore.
那你是谁
Well, who are you?
我还没名字
I have no designation yet.
当我完成时就会有了
I'll be given one when I'm complete.
若楠怎么了
What about Ronon?
你指那个入侵者?
You mean the intruder?
他还活着  暂时
He's alive, for the moment.
他即将被消灭
He's been neutralized.
我能感觉到他的脉搏
I can feel his pulse.
很弱
It's weak.
只需轻轻攥一下就能结束
It would only take the slightest squeeze.
你不能这么做
Yeah, but you don't want to do that
你们是一伙儿的记得吗
because he's one of you, remember?
让她说话
Keep her talking.
你去哪儿?
Where are you going?
结束这一切
I'm going to go finish this.
珍妮弗  我是卡森
Jennifer, this is Carson.
贝克特博士  我说过了
Dr. Beckett, I already told you,
我已经不是珍妮弗·凯勒了
I'm not jennifer keller anymore.
她能听到你的声音
You're the voice she was hearing,
你只是控制了她大脑的语言功能
the part of her mind that was taking over.
你们阻止不了我
You can't stop me.
我将会如期完成
I will become as I was meant to be.
谢帕德上校启动了小飞船
Colonel Sheppard is powering up a jumper.
给我一条安全频道
Get me a secure channel.
谢帕德  你在干嘛
Sheppard, what are you doing?
抄点近路
I'm taking a little short-cut.
抱歉我来不及填申请文件了
Sorry I didn't have time to fill out the paperwork.
好了  我看见了
Okay, I see it now.
这东西到处都是了
That stuff is growing all over the place.
这可能有点疼
This may hurt.
谢帕德上校  请回复
Colonel Sheppard, report.
谢帕德上校?
Colonel Sheppard?
谢帕德上校  报告你的情况
Colonel Sheppard, what's your status?
谢帕德上校...
Colonel Sheppard...
我好很多了
I've been better.
发生了什么
What happened?
你最好派人来接我们
You'd better come get us.
若楠怎么样
How's Ronon?
他喉部损伤
He has a bruised larynx.
显然他要有几天不能说话了
Apparently he won't be able to speak for several days.
大概没几个人会发现都什么不同
I wonder if anyone will notice the difference.
谢帕德上校?
Colonel Sheppard?
看看谁从隔离室出来了
Look who's finally out of isolation.
很高兴看到你  医生
Oh, it's good to see you, doc.
你感觉怎样
How you feeling?
就是呼吸时有点疼
It only hurts when I breathe.
这感觉可不好
I feel really bad.
好像我的恢复
It looks like my recovery's going to be
比你还快
a lot easier than yours.
那没什么
That's all right.
现在有两个医生照顾我
I've got two doctors looking after me now.
我想你误会了
Well, no, I'm afraid not.
我今天下午就要走了
I'm scheduled to leave this afternoon.
当然  除非
That is, unless of course
未来一小时内又出现了巨大的险情
there's a major crisis in the next hour or so.
那样也不会令我吃惊
It wouldn't surprise me.
好了  你自己要小心点
Well, listen, you keep yourself out of trouble,
我们马上就会再见的
and I'll see you real soon.
祝你好运  卡森
Good luck, carson.
谢了  约翰
Thanks, John.
欢迎回来  凯勒医生
Welcome back, Dr. Keller,
贝克特博士
and Dr. Beckett...
谢谢
Thank you.
太客气了  伍尔希先生
My pleasure, Mr. Woolsey.
我下来之前
Before I came down here,
刚和以前在地球的上级通了电话
I was on a call with my superiors back on earth.
他们在审查我的初步报告
They were going over my preliminary report.
你说了什么
What did you tell them?
真相
The truth.
我只做了三天的总指挥
That in my first three days as commander,
我违反了至少一半的安全条例
I violated at least half a dozen basic security protocols.
有那么多?
That many, huh?
我让贝克特来做这项调查
I let Beckett run the investigation,
不考虑他的身体状况
in spite of his condition and the fact that
而且他已经不算是探险队的成员了
he's technically no longer a member of this expedition.
我让若楠去分发解毒剂了
I sent Ronon to deliver the antidote
尽管他也被感染了
even though he was infected.
我牺牲基地的安全
I compromised the safety of this base
来解救一个可能救不了的人
to rescue someone who may well have been beyond our help anyway.
但她不是
But she wasn't,
而且我们把她救出来了
and we got her out.
如果你死板教条
And if you had played by the rules,
她早就死了
she'd be dead right now.
勘查组织可能会同意你的看法
The IOA would seem to agree with you.
显然  他们想大事化小小事化了
Apparently, they're willing to let the matter drop.
那还有什么问题
So, what's the problem?
各项准则都有它存在的理由  上校
The rules are there for a reason, Colonel.
如果我不能照做  那...
If I can't trust them, then...
我觉得我无法胜任这个工作
I'm not sure I can do this job.
欢迎来到飞马座星系
Welcome to the Pegasus Galaxy.